- 舰长 - 怎么了，韦伯？
- Captain. - What is it, Webb?
屏幕上出现不明物体，长官
A blip, sir. Just came on the screen.
探测出是什么吗？
How do you read it?
某种飞行物
Aircraft of some sort.
从大小和速度来看
By the size of it and the speed,
不是我们的，我以前从未见过
it's not one of ours, sir. It doesn't even read like anything I've ever seen.
- 从哪跑出来的？ - 不知道，长官
- What was the approach? - None, sir. It was just there,
就好像从天上突然冒了出来
like it fell out of the sky or something.
当前位置？
Current position?
停在奥马哈基地上空，长官
Directly over the Omaha installation, sir. Holding there.
韦伯，继续监控
Watch the scope, Webb. Air Defence will wanna send somebody up
空防署会派人上去近距离观察
to get a closer look.
看来是遇上UFO了
I think we have a real UFO on our hands.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: to explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：胖收儿 毛毛要长肉
校对：kmdangdangli
第一季第十九集
明日即往昔
舰长日志，星历313.2
Captain's log, stardate 313.2.
我们正前往9号星际基地补给，遇到一颗黑色星球
We were en route to starbase 9 for resupply when a black star
其巨大引力把我们越拉越近
of high gravitational attraction began to drag us toward it.
我们用尽一切曲速动力才将其挣脱
It required all warp power in reverse to pull us away from the star.
可就像射弹弓一样
But, like snapping a rubber band,
飞船猛地弹了出去，失去了控制
the breakaway sent us plunging through space, out of control,
不知何时停下，飞向何方
to stop here, wherever we are.
- 情况如何，史波克？ - 除了辅助系统
- Mr. Spock? - Except for secondary systems,
一切动力都没了，只能靠脉冲动力了
everything is out, sir. We're on impulse power only.
备用设备呢？
Auxiliaries?
史考特没事的话，马上就能启动备用设备
If Mr. Scott is still with us, auxiliaries should be on momentarily.
上尉，你还好吗？
Are you all right, lieutenant?
史考特没事
Mr. Scott is still with us.
我是舰长
This is the captain.
各损害防控部门，紧急集合
Damage-control parties on all decks, check in.
各部门注意，更新记录
All departments, tie in with the record computer.
向大副汇报人员伤亡及战备状态
Report casualties and operational readiness to the first officer.
完毕
Kirk out.
乌乎拉上尉
Lieutenant Uhura...
通知星际舰队控制中心
...contact Starfleet Control.
注意黑色星球的位置
I want them alerted to the position of that black star
- 位于9号基地附近 - 是，长官
- in the area of Starbase 9. - Yes, sir.
舰长，伤亡报告表明只有轻伤
Captain, casualty reports indicate only minor injuries.
工程报告显示曲速引擎无法运转
Engineering reports warp engines non-operational.
史考特修改了轮机的自动飞行模式
Mr. Scott overrode the automatic helm setting
目前我们是靠脉冲动力运行
and is holding us in orbit on impulse power.
- 运行在哪条轨道，史波克？ - 地球，舰长
- Orbit where, Mr. Spock? - Earth, captain.
我们被牵制时
We were on a general course in this direction
就是朝地球方向挣脱的
when we were pulled in by the star.
挣脱后自然就会飞向地球
Apparently, the breakaway threw us on in the same direction.
开启显示屏
Screen on.
我们在大气中的位置太低，就快脱离运行轨道了
We are too low in the atmosphere to retain this orbit, captain.
工程报告显示脉冲动力可产生
Engineering reports we have sufficient impulse power
- 足够的逃逸速度 - 苏鲁，再飞高点
- to achieve escape velocity. - Give us some altitude, Mr. Sulu.
是，长官，启动舵轮
Yes, sir. Helm answering.
- 反应有点慢，长官 - 舰长
- She's sluggish, sir. - Captain,
星际舰队的常用频道受静电干扰
normal Starfleet channel has nothing on it but static.
其他频率有反馈，但不是星际舰队发出的
I'm getting something on another frequency, but it's not Starfleet.
开启音频
Put it on audio.
现在是五点半新闻摘要，来自肯尼迪角发射站
This is the 5:30 news summary, Cape Kennedy.
首次载人探月计划定于
The first manned moonshot is scheduled
美国东部时间星期三上午六点
for Wednesday, 6 a.m. Eastern Standard Time.
担任此次历史性飞行的三名宇航员…
All three astronauts who are to make this historic--
载人探月？
Manned moonshot?
那是60年代末的事了
That was in the late 1960s.
显然，舰长，我们也是
Apparently, captain, so are we.
什么？
What?
挣脱的力量使我们穿越了时空，回到过去
Whiplash propelled us into a time warp, captain, backward.
计时器正读取确切年代
Exact chronometer readings in a few moments.
舰长…
Captain...
收到地对空信号
...I'm getting ground-to-air transmission.
没错，扫描显示有飞行物从下方接近我们
Verified. Scanners report some type of craft approaching from below us
在云层下面，越来越近
under cloud cover and closing.
黑鹰呼叫蓝鸟四号，我们正追踪你和UFO
Blue Jay Four, this is Blackjack. We're tracking both you and the UFO.
屏幕显示目标锁定
I have him on my screen. Following.
苏鲁，能快点升高吗？我想甩开他们
Mr. Sulu, can you gain altitude faster? I want to outdistance them.
提速了，长官，就是反应有点慢
Picking up, sir, but she's just slow in responding.
蓝鸟呼叫黑鹰
Blackjack, this is Blue Jay Four.
UFO正提高速度和高度
UFO is picking up speed and climbing.
我在努力接近
I'm going in closer.
蓝鸟四号，目标已进入你的视线范围
Blue Jay Four, you should be close enough for visual contact.
我看到了
I can see it now.
这玩意儿可真大
Whatever this thing is, it's big.
上方有两个柱状凸物，下方有一个
Two cylindrical projections on top, one below.
用途不明
Purpose undetermined.
已紧急增派两架飞机，正在途中
We have two flights scrambled and on the way.
两分钟后与你汇合
They should rendezvous in your sector in two minutes.
来不及了，UFO正快速上升
Won't be here. The UFO is climbing away fast.
蓝鸟四号，现命你接近UFO
Blue Jay Four, you are ordered to close on the UFO
并使其迫降，增援飞机来前
and attempt to force him to land. We want it brought down
我们必须牵制住它
or at least disabled until the other planes arrive.
收到，朝目标接近
Acknowledged. Closing on target.
识别没错，舰长
Positive identification, captain.
是架装有导弹的拦截机
Aircraft is an interceptor equipped with missiles,
有可能还装有核弹头
possibly armed with nuclear warheads.
一旦击中我们，损坏会很严重
If he hits us with one, he might damage us severely.
在当前情况下很可能无法修复
Perhaps beyond our capacity to repair under current circumstances.
史考特，启动牵引波束
Scotty, activate tractor beam.
锁定那架飞机，别让它动
Lock onto that aircraft and hold it out there.
舰长，这种飞机恐怕太脆弱
Captain, this type of aircraft might be too fragile
- 无法抵御牵引光束 - 已开启牵引
- to take our tractor beam. - Tractor beam on, sir.
锁定目标
We have the target.
飞机解体了，舰长
Aircraft is breaking up, captain.
传送室
Transporter Room,
能锁定那架飞机的驾驶舱吗？
can you lock onto the cockpit of that aircraft?
正扫描区域，长官
Scanning area, sir.
把飞行员送上来，接管一下，史波克
Try and beam that pilot aboard. Take over, Mr. Spock.
欢迎来到进取号
Welcome aboard the Enterprise.
- 你说英语 - 对
- You speak English. - That's right.
- 你可以从传送器上下来… - 约翰·克里斯托弗上校
- You can step off the transporter-- - Captain John Christopher,
美国空军，编号4857932
United States Air Force, serial number 4857932.
放松，上校，我们没有敌意
Relax, captain. You're among friends.
我是寇克舰长
I'm Captain James T. Kirk.
这是怎么回事？
What's going on here?
这是哪儿？发生了什么？
Where am I? What happened?
你们是谁？
You people, who are you?
你会知道的，上校，同时…
All in good time, captain. Meanwhile...
如此唐突地把你带上来，还请见谅
...let me apologise for bringing you aboard the ship so abruptly,
但道歉也没用了，我不知道你的飞机
but it couldn't be helped. I didn't know that your craft
抵挡不了我们的牵引力
couldn't stand up to our tractor beam--
少废话，告诉我你是谁
Don't give me any double talk. Just tell me who you are.
等我们决定好，一会儿就告诉你
We'll tell you what we decide to tell you in a few moments.
同时，别紧张，你是我们的客人
In the meantime, relax. You're our guest.
你会觉得这件事很有趣
I have a feeling you'll find it interesting.
- 舰桥呼叫寇克舰长 - 我是寇克，怎么了，史波克？
- Bridge to Captain Kirk. - Kirk here. What is it, Mr. Spock?
那架飞机彻底坏了，舰长
The aircraft has completely broken up, captain.
- 是否可以关闭牵引光束？ - 可以
- Shall we turn off the tractor beam? - Affirmative.
飞行员上来了
We have the pilot aboard.
我马上到，完毕
I'll be right up. Kirk out.
跟我来
Follow me.
- 早，舰长 - 早，舰长
- Good morning, captain. - Good morning. Captain.
- 女人？ - 是船员
- A woman? - Crewman.
舰桥
Bridge.
造这样一艘船得花不少功夫吧？
Must have taken quite a lot to build a ship like this.
舰队里只有12艘这样的船
There are only 12 like it in the fleet.
这样啊
I see.
- 怎么海军…？ - 我们是联勤，上校
- Did the Navy--? - We're a combined service, captain.
我们的上级是全球联合太空探索局
Our authority is the United Earth Space Probe Agency.
全球联合？
United Earth?
这很难解释
This is very difficult to explain.
我们来自于未来
We're from your future.
时间隧道把我们带到这儿
A time warp placed us here.
- 是个意外 - 你们似乎有过不少意外
- It was an accident. - You seem to have a lot of them.
可我不能否认你们的确在这儿，还有这艘船
However, I can't deny the fact that you are here, with this ship.
我从不相信世上有外星人
I never have believed in little green men.
我也不相信
Neither have I.
克里斯托弗上校，这是我的大副，史波克少校
Captain Christopher, this is my first officer, Lieutenant Commander Spock.
上校
Captain.
随便看，上校，别去碰
Feel free to look around, captain. Don't touch anything,
你一定会觉得很有趣
but I think you'll find it interesting.
“有趣”一词根本无法形容，舰长
"Interesting" is a word and a half for it, captain.
我们已在大气层上方的轨道稳定运行
We've achieved a stable orbit out of Earth's atmosphere.
我们的导向板运转正常
Our deflectors are operative, enough to prevent
我们不会再被当做UFO受到跟踪了
our being picked up again as a UFO.
史考特想跟你说说发动机的事
And Mr. Scott wishes to speak to you about the engines.
很好，史波克
Very well, Mr. Spock.
你在想什么？
Anything else on your mind?
克里斯托弗上校
Captain Christopher.
他怎么了？
What about him?
我们不能送他回地球，舰长
We cannot return him to Earth, captain.
他知道得太多，还会更多
He already knows too much about us and is learning more.
我不是针对克里斯托弗上校
I do not specifically refer to Captain Christopher,
但设想一个图谋不轨的人要是掌握了
but suppose an unscrupulous man were to gain certain knowledge
人类未来的知识
of man's future.
各个行业、股票、甚至国家就会由他操控
Such a man could manipulate key industries, stocks and even nations,
未来也因此改变
and in so doing, change what must be.
一旦改变，舰长
And if it is changed, captain,
你和我还有我们所知的一切都不复存在
you and I and all that we know might not even exist.
你的逻辑有时真…
Your logic can be most...
烦人
...annoying.
那身飞行服一定不舒服
That flight suit must be uncomfortable.
让舵手给他备件舒服点的
Why don't you have the quartermaster issue him something more suitable.
之后你和他来我房间见我
And then I'll want to meet you and him in my quarters.
遵命
Yes, sir.
电脑开始记录
Computer on. Record.
记录开始
Recording.
进来
Come.
舰长日志，补充
Captain's log, supplemental.
轮机长史考特报告曲速引擎坏了
Engineering Officer Scott informs warp engines damaged,
但修复后便能重新启动
but can be made operational and re-energised.
记录完毕，亲爱的
Computed and recorded, dear.
电脑，你不能那样叫我，记录
Computer, you will not address me in that manner. Compute.
已记录，亲爱的
Computed, dear.
史波克，这台电脑的电路系统怎么还没修好？
Mr. Spock, I ordered this computer and its interlinking systems repaired.
我检查过了，舰长
I have investigated it, captain.
要修好就得重新
To correct the fault will require an overhaul
对整台电脑进行全面检测
of the entire computer system,
还得在星际基地，花至少三周
a minimum of three weeks at a starbase.
要是它说话不这么暧昧
I wouldn't mind so much if only it didn't get so...
我也不会太介意
...affectionate.
不幸的是它还老喜欢咯咯傻笑
It also has an unfortunate tendency to giggle.
我猜这位计算机女士有点毛病？
I take it that a lady computer is not routine?
它在小天鹅14号星球做过常规维修
We put it in at Cygnet XIV for general repair and maintenance.
小天鹅十四号星由女性掌管
Cygnet XIV is a planet dominated by women.
她们觉得飞船的电脑系统缺乏人性
They seem to feel the ship's computer system lacked a personality.
便赋予了它人性，当然是女性
They gave it one. Female, of course.
你们这些人手头上的问题真有趣
Well, you people certainly have interesting problems.
我很想继续看你“女朋友”如何搞定，可…
I'd love to stay around to see how your girlfriend works out, but--
恐怕你必须继续呆着
I'm afraid you'll have to.
我们不能把你送回去
We can't send you back.
不能？
Can't?
史波克说过，即使在这么高的轨道
Spock here told me that your transporter can beam down
你们的传送器也能把东西送下去
an object even from an orbit this high.
不是传送器的问题，是你
It's not the transporter, it's you.
你知道未来的样子
You know what the future looks like.
要是让别人也知道
If anybody else finds out,
他们便会改变它，毁掉它
they could change the course of it, destroy it.
可我的消失也会造成改变
Well, then my disappearance would change something too.
我用电脑把所有历史记录查了一遍
I have run a computer check on all historical tapes.
约翰·克里斯托弗并无作为
They show no record of any relevant contribution
故没有他的相关记录
by John Christopher.
听着，舰长，我不相信你们所谓的“穿越事故”
Look, captain, I don't buy all of your "time accident" story.
现在的专家能查出你们是谁，干什么的
Now, the experts can figure out who you are, what you are.
我有责任汇报我的所见
It's my duty to report what I've seen.
换成你，会怎么做？
Well, what would you do?
我也会…
I'd...
汇报
...report...
可惜我们不会冒这个险
...if I could. We can't take the risk.
我不想听什么冒险，我有老婆孩子
I don't want to know about risks. I have a wife, two children.
他们怎么办？
What about them?
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
轮机室呼叫寇克舰长
Engine Room to Captain Kirk.
我是寇克，怎么了，史考特？
Kirk here. What is it, Scotty?
进度报告
Progress report, sir.
虽然很仓促，但维修初见成效
Everything's jury-rigged, but we're coming along with the repairs.
四小时内便可启动，但…
We should be able to re-energise in about four hours, but...
- 但是什么，史考特？ - 我刚刚说过
- But what, Scotty? - Well, sir, as I say...
引擎还在维修中…
...the engines are being repaired...
但在此期间我们无处可去
...but we've no place to go in this time.
如果你明白我的意思
If you-- If you see what I mean.
长官？
Sir?
好的，史考特，接着修
Yes, Scotty. Carry on.
太糟了，舰长
Too bad, captain.
也许我回不了家，你们也一样
Maybe I can't go home, but neither can you.
你们和我一样成了时间的囚犯
You're as much a prisoner in time as I am.
舰长日志，星历3113.7
Captain's log, stardate 3113.7.
引擎就快修好了，但我们仍被时间所困
Our engines are being repaired, but we are still locked in time,
船上还来了位不速之客
and we have aboard a passenger whom we do not want
我们回不去了
and we cannot return.
得考虑如何处置他，亲爱的
Recommendation for his disposition, dear.
接着记录
Maintenance note.
我的记录电脑出现严重故障
My recording computer has a serious malfunction.
建议要么修改要么销毁记录
Recommend it either be corrected or scrapped. Compute.
已记录
Computed.
舰桥呼叫寇克舰长
Bridge to Captain Kirk.
- 我是寇克 - 关于克里斯托弗上校…
- Kirk here. - Have some new information
有新的信息
regarding Captain Christopher.
很重要，我要立即见你们
Important I see you both immediately.
好，史波克，来我房间汇报
Yes, Mr. Spock. Report to my quarters.
- 我去叫克里斯托弗上校 - 好的，舰长，通话完毕
- I'll contact Captain Christopher. - Yes, sir. Bridge out.
克里斯托弗上校
Captain Christopher.
- 警卫处，我是舰长 - 我是警卫处负责人
- Security, this is the captain. - Security chief here, sir.
全员警戒，克里斯托弗上校不在他的房间
All decks alert. Captain Christopher is not in his assigned quarters.
他也许正试图逃脱，立即派人
He may be trying to escape. I want a man outside
去传送室，我随即就来
the Transporter Room immediately. I'm heading there myself.
别动，乖乖听话
All right, nice and easy.
我走到那玩意儿里
Now, I'm gonna step into that thing,
你就把我送回地球
and you're gonna transport me back to Earth.
除了轻微的擦伤
Well, Jim, with the exception of a slight bruise or two,
我们这位上校健壮如牛
our captain is as healthy as a proverbial horse.
- 一分钟后他就会苏醒 - 他想逃跑
- He'll be coming out of it in a minute. - He tried to escape.
我理解他的感受，可不能让他这么回去
I know how he feels, but I can't send him back with what he knows.
吉姆，如果我们回不去怎么办？
Jim, what if we can't go back?
该怎么办？坐以待毙，等着供给耗尽？
What do we do, sit up here and wait for our supplies to run out,
等动力用尽？这是迟早的事
our power to die? It has to eventually, you know,
我们也不能去地球
and we certainly can't go back to Earth. That would be worse
这比让上校回去更可怕，这里有430个人呢
than the captain being returned. There are 430 of us.
这意味着430个改变未来的机会
Now, that means 430 chances of altering the future.
对
Yes.
- 我们现在还没那么糟 - 听着还算欣慰
- We're not in that position yet. - I'm glad to hear it.
如果我们回到我们的年代
And if we do get back to where we belong,
他将无法适应
then he won't belong.
虽然我们同龄，但在我们的社会
We're roughly about the same age, but in our society,
他会变得一无是处，就像个老古董
he'd be useless, archaic.
但也许他可以重新接受训练和教育
But maybe he could be retrained, reeducated.
你说话怎么跟史波克似的
Now you're sounding like Spock.
你再拿我开涮，我可走人了
If you're gonna get nasty, I'm gonna leave.
训练能让他忘掉家庭和孩子吗？
Could he be retrained to forget his family, his children?
答案是不能
The answer to that is no.
- 你还好吗？ - 嗯
- You all right? - Yeah.
我发现你们也要求体能训练
I see physical training is required in your service too.
虽然粗鲁，却很见效
Crude methods, but effective.
- 他什么意思？ - 开个玩笑，上校
- What does he mean by that? - It's just a joke, captain.
你获得了什么新信息，史波克？
You said you had some additional information, Mr. Spock?
我在计算中犯了个错
I made an error in my computations.
真是难得啊
This could be an historic occasion.
必须要把克里斯托弗上校送回地球
I find that we must return Captain Christopher to Earth after all.
为什么？你说我无所作为
Why? You said I made no relative contribution.
是我说错了
A poor choice of words on my part.
我在初次查阅时忽视了…
I neglected, in my initial run-through,
后代有可能做出的相关贡献
to correlate the possible contributions by offspring.
多方查阅后，我发现
I find, after running a crosscheck on that factor,
你儿子，肖恩·杰弗里·克里斯托弗上校
that your son, Colonel Shaun Geoffrey Christopher,
带队，或者说将会带队成功完成首个土星探测的任务
headed, or will head, the first successful Earth-Saturn probe,
- 这意义非常重大… - 等等，我没有儿子
- which is a rather significant-- - Wait a minute. I don't have a son.
是还没有
You mean, yet.
医生是对的
The doctor is correct.
不把克里斯托弗上校送回地球
Unless we return Captain Christopher to Earth,
肖恩·杰弗里·克里斯托弗上校就不会去探测土星
there will be no Colonel Shaun Geoffrey Christopher to go to Saturn.
就这些吗？
Well, that's it, isn't it.
我们得想办法…
We'll have to find some way of--
是个男孩
A boy.
我会有个儿子
I'm going to have a son.
虽然克里斯托弗上校必须被送回去
Acknowledging that we must return Captain Christopher,
但还有些尚未解决的问题
there are several problems...
最主要的是如何解释他的返回
...prime of which is the explanation of his return.
牵引光束击毁他的飞机后，我们追踪了飞机残骸
We tracked his plane wreckage down after our tractor beam crushed it.
位于南内布拉斯加一片开阔的区域
It crashed in an open section of southern Nebraska.
这意味着搜救队会对残骸进行全面搜查
That means those search parties will be crawling all over that wreckage.
而克里斯托弗上校使情况变得更复杂
And Captain Christopher himself complicated the matter.
我一看见你们就打开了机翼摄像头
When I made visual contact, I turned on my wing cameras,
因为距离很近，我照了几张清晰的图像
and I got close enough to take some pretty clear pictures of you.
防空司令部会迅速分析图像
Air Defence Command will be processing that film fast.
而且控制中心还录下了我的传输信号
And ADC Control was probably recording my radio transmissions.
我记得历史上把外星飞船解释为
If I remember my history, these things were being dismissed
气象气球或幻日导致的假象
as weather balloons, sundogs,
这种解释很合理，至少对公众是如此
explainable things, at least publicly.
舰长，我们的牵引光速摧毁的可是架军用飞机
Captain, our tractor beam caught and crushed an Air Force plane.
除了解释为UFO之外，我们别无选择
It'll be impossible to explain us as anything other than a genuine UFO,
而且还是极具毁灭性的的外星人
possibly alien, definitely destructive.
那我们的问题怎么办，史波克先生？
What about our problem, Mr. Spock?
有办法回到我们的年代吗？
Any ideas on how to get us back to our own time?
有一个理论
A theory.
便是消除过去发生的事
A reverse application of what happened to us.
逻辑上行得通
Logically, it could work.
但逻辑上还存在上百种变数
Also, logically, there are a hundred variables,
随便一种都会使情况更糟
any one of which could put us in a worse position than we're in now.
我们得回去拿那些报告和照片
We're gonna have to go back and get those reports and photos.
若上校被要求据实禀报
If the captain feels duty-bound to report what he saw,
便没有任何支撑的证据
there won't be any evidence to back him up.
我也只好撒谎，或者装傻
That makes me out to be either a liar or a fool.
- 或许吧 - 不尽然
- Perhaps. - Not at all.
你只不过是众多自称见过UFO的人之一
You'll simply be one of the thousands who thought he saw a UFO.
舰长，我了解基地
Captain, I know that base.
一年前我就在那里驻扎
I was stationed there a year ago.
- 我想… - 不，上校
- I'd like to-- - No, captain.
谢谢，可万一有差池，你会受伤的
Thank you, but if anything should go wrong, you might get hurt.
我们不能拿你或你的儿子去冒险
We couldn't risk that. Neither can you or your son.
就让我出分力吧
Well, I'd like to help.
我能画张那里的布局图
I can sketch a layout of the place for you.
标出档案部及照片实验室的方位
Show you where the records section and the photo lab are.
电脑很原始
Primitive computer.
我在博物馆见过
I've seen them demonstrated in museums.
我也是，这种电脑一启动
Me too. And if this one's like those, it'll make the devil's own noise
- 就会响声如雷 - 我可不想启动它
- if you start it. - I don't intend to start it.
他们下去多久了？
How long have they been down there now?
15分28秒
Fifteen minutes, 28 seconds.
该上来了吧？
Well, shouldn't they be coming up?
其实，偷偷摸摸的行动比直接的方式
It is a fact, doctor, that prowling by stealth is more time-consuming
更花时间，就我们的情况…
than a direct approach. In our case--
你不是该去计算时间曲速的吗，史波克？
Shouldn't you be working on your time-warp calculations, Mr. Spock?
我正算着呢
I am.
别动，举起手来
Hold it. Get your hands up.
一次一件，把腰上的东西交出来
Now, one at a time, hand me those belts.
还有袋子
And the bag.
太久了，吉姆至少该回个话
It's been too long. Jim should've at least signalled by now.
或许你是对的，大夫，开启通讯频道
You may be correct, doctor. Open communicator channel.
那是什么？
What was that?
- 什么？ - 那声音
- What was what? - That noise.
我什么都没听见
I didn't hear anything.
那声音，是从这些东西里发出的
That noise. It's coming from one of these things.
是紧急信号
The emergency signal.
- 站着别动 - 收到紧急信号，长官
- Stay right where you are. - One emergency signal, sir.
立即把人带上来
Beam up, immediately.
- 怎么就只有一人发出？ - 一会儿就知道了，大夫
- Only one signal. What happened? - We'll know in a moment, doctor.
寇克呼叫进取号
Kirk to Enterprise.
我是史波克，你好吗，舰长？
Spock here. Are you all right, captain?
我没事，但如你所见
Yes, I'm all right. But as you can see,
咱们又多了个麻烦
we have another problem.
舰长日志，星历3113.9
Captain's log, stardate 3113.9.
史波克大副记录
First Officer Spock recording.
由于一次不幸的事故
Due to an unfortunate accident,
船上又多了名不速之客
we have taken aboard another unwanted passenger.
送你的惊喜是基地一名空勤中士
Your surprise package is an air police sergeant from the base.
在传送室看好他
Keep him in the Transporter Room.
别让他看见舰上其他东西
No sense in letting him see more of the ship than necessary.
舰长，我想这个不会有问题
I don't believe there'll be any trouble in that respect, captain.
我们的客人似乎很愿意原地不动
Our guest seems quite satisfied to remain where he is.
好的，完毕
All right, Kirk out.
第一次看到克里斯托弗的飞机时
What was the chronometer reading
天文计时器读数是多少？
when we first sighted Christopher's jet?
当地时间5:30，可能更晚一点
Five-thirty in that time zone, maybe a little after.
那就该是这些，都拿走
That would put it at the end of these tapes. We've got them all.
去暗室找找
We'll try the darkroom.
照片实验室
Photo lab.
就是这个
That's it.
就是这些
That's all of them.
发信号给史波克，告诉他我们准备登舰
Signal Mr. Spock that we're almost ready to beam up.
保险起见，我去查查文档
I'll make a check of the files just in case.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
- 还有一个呢？ - 什么？
- All right, where's the other one? - What other one?
你的搭档，我见你朝那边看
Your partner. I saw you looking that way,
- 我见那边有人在动 - 不，只有我
- and I saw somebody move in there. - Oh, no, no. Just me.
再说谁能在你眼皮底下溜走呢？
Besides, could anyone get out of here without your seeing them?
的确谁都溜不走
No. Nobody should've been able to.
你登舰的决定是正确的，苏鲁
Your decision to beam up was quite correct, Mr. Sulu.
轮机室呼叫史波克
Engine Room to Mr. Spock.
我是史波克
Spock here.
曲速引擎已获得动力，长官
We've completed re-energizing the warp engines, sir.
- 随时可以启动 - 现在就启动，轮机师
- We can refire them any time. - Do so now, engineer.
验证理论需要足够动力
We'll need all the power to test our theory.
是，长官，通话完毕
Aye, sir. Engine Room out.
拍得很糟
Poor photography.
去你的理论和观察！史波克
Blast your theories and observations, Mr. Spock.
吉姆怎么办？他还在下面，也许被抓了
What about Jim? He's down there alone, probably under arrest.
他没有通讯器，我们无法定位他
He doesn't have a communicator, and we can't locate him
也没法把他带回来
or beam him back aboard without one.
我知道，医生
I am aware of that, doctor.
我是大副
This is the first officer.
把克里斯托弗上校带去简报室
Captain Christopher to the Briefing Room.
我说先生，咱俩得聊聊
Now, look, mister. You and I had better start communicating.
我要知道你是怎么进来的？问题很简单
I want to know how you got in here. Now, that's a simple question.
简单地回答我，没人看见你
Give me a simple answer. Nobody saw you.
你没触发任何警报就能进来
You got all the way inside here without tripping any alarm.
- 是怎么做到的？ - 相信我，上校…
- How did you do it? - Believe me, colonel...
- 你是不会相信我的 - 别耍花样
- ...you wouldn't believe me. - Now, don't try to be funny.
你怎么进来的？
How did you get in?
我从天上突然一下就到这了
I popped in out of thin air.
看来你把这事当成儿戏
You seem to think this is some kind of a game.
不，上校，我知道这不是儿戏
No, colonel, I know it's no game.
好吧，你叫什么来着？
All right, what did you say your name was?
都第四遍了，我叫詹姆士·T·寇克
For the fourth time, my name is James T. Kirk.
你是如何来到
And how did you get inside
这个严密戒备的军事基地，詹姆士·T·寇克？
a top-security installation, James T. Kirk?
我说过了，你又不相信
I've told you, you wouldn't believe me.
上校，那个东西请轻拿轻放
Colonel, would you mind being careful with that?
这让你担心啦？这是什么？收音机？
That worries you a little bit, huh? What is it, a radio?
- 某种发报机？ - 差不多
- Transmitter of some kind? - Of some kind.
说详细点，寇克
You can be more specific than that, Kirk.
我不喜欢猜谜
I don't like mysteries.
如果你还毛手毛脚，你就会惹上事
You don't stop being careless with that, and you'll have one.
而且还是大事
A big one.
我会把它拆掉检查
I'll have it disassembled and examined.
我们可不傻，先生
We are not dummies, mister.
我们知道如何探究欲知之事
We know how to find out things we want to know.
这是什么？
What is that?
制服吗？
Is that a uniform of some kind?
这小身衣服吗？
This little thing?
就是我随便穿穿的
Something I slipped on.
寇克，你没意识到这有多严重
Kirk, maybe you don't realise how serious this is.
破坏政府军事驻地…
Sabotage of a government installation--
- 我破坏什么了吗？ - 没，在我们及时的阻止下
- Did I sabotage something? - No. We stopped you in time.
要不是我们发现的话，你会做什么？
But what would you have done if we hadn't found you?
相信我，上校，什么都不会
Believe me, colonel, nothing at all.
这就是你来这的目的？什么都不做？
Is that what you're here for? Nothing at all?
你们不干涉的话，本可如此的
That's what would've happened if you hadn't interfered.
看来你是不见棺材不落泪啊
All right, Kirk, maybe this will make you laugh.
蓄意破坏，间谍活动，私闯以及偷窃罪
Sabotage, espionage, unauthorised entry, burglary.
先上几道开胃菜，要是还不交代
How are those for starters? And I can think up lots more
- 我还能再想出几个来 - 好吧，上校
- if you don't start talking. - All right, colonel.
其实我是来自半人马座阿尔法星的外星人
The truth is, I'm a little green man from Alpha Centauri,
那里很美，你真该去看看
a beautiful place. You ought to see it.
我真该把你关个两百年
I am going to lock you up for 200 years.
就该这么干
That ought to be just about right.
他应该是被关在警卫处
He's probably being held in Security Section.
即使他们已通报上级
Even if they've notified the authorities,
上面派人去那儿，还得花点时间
it'll take a little time for someone to get there.
很对，上校，我们要派登陆小队下去
Quite logical, captain. Can you give us the coordinates
你能把审讯室附近的坐标告诉我们吗？
to beam down a landing party near those interrogation rooms?
能
Yes.
但必须带上我，否则别想知道
But you're not going to get them unless you take me with you.
- 我不能这么做，上校 - 万一出了差错…
- I can't do that, captain. - If something went wrong--
已经出差错了
Something's already gone wrong.
你们当然也可以自己去基地
Of course, you could beam down anywhere inside that base,
但找到他就得花点时间
but it would take time to find him.
苏鲁，你和克里斯托弗上校随我下去
Mr. Sulu, you and Captain Christopher will beam down with me.
坐标由上校告诉传送员
The captain will provide the coordinates for the transporter chief.
- 要带相位枪吗？ - 你一把，我一把
- Shall I issue phasers? - One for you, one for me.
- 调到重度击晕模式 - 是，长官
- Set them on heavy stun force. - Yes, sir.
你不信任我，史波克
You don't trust me, Spock.
事实上我相信
In fact, I do.
但不是完全相信
But only to a certain point.
开始传送
Energise.
他们经常这么干？
Do they do that all the time?
饿吗？
Are you hungry?
想吃点什么？
What would you like?
来点鸡汤吧
Maybe some chicken soup.
真是鸡汤
It is.
等一下，先生，站住
Just a minute, sir. Hold it.
去看看怎么回事
See what that is, airman.
你的手就不疼吗，舰长？
Don't you find that painful, captain?
当然疼啦，他来干什么？
Yes, I do. What's he doing here?
他知道这里的传送坐标
He knew the beam-down coordinates for this section of the base.
- 有必要带他来 - 明白了，也没啥不好
- It was necessary to bring him along. - I see. Well, no harm done.
苏鲁，带子检查过了吗？
Mr. Sulu. Did you have a chance to check out those tapes?
史波克在电脑上查过了
Mr. Spock ran them through our computers.
全是我们要找的
They were the right ones. We got them all.
他们知道你来过这
They know you've been here.
可留下的只是个解不开的谜
All they have is a mystery and no answers.
苏鲁，通知传送员
Mr. Sulu, signal the transporter chief.
- 有四人登舰 - 是，长官
- Four to beam up. - Aye, sir.
除了我
Not me.
别做傻事
Don't be a fool.
- 你知道事关重大 - 我当然知道
- You know what's at stake. - You bet I do.
我的家庭，未出生的儿子
My family, a son that isn't born yet.
我现在回来了就不走了，舰长
You don't have to return me now, captain.
- 史波克，从里面出来 - 你这样出现在基地
- Spock, come out of there. - You can't explain your presence
- 怎么解释？ - 我说过，我的职责是如实禀报
- on the base. - I told you, it's my duty to report
我见到的一切，这解释足够了
everything I've seen. That's explanation enough.
- 史波克！ - 你会回家的，克里斯托弗…
- Spock! - You'll go home, Christopher...
但得按我们的方式
...but you'll do it our way.
没门
Over my dead body.
我就猜他不愿跟我们回去
I suspected he might not wish to return with us.
- 四人登舰，苏鲁 - 是，长官
- Four to beam up, Mr. Sulu. - Yes, sir.
舰长日志，星历3114.1
Captain's log, stardate 3114.1.
我们必须穿越这个年代
We must make an attempt to break free of this time
否则我们和那两位不太听话的乘客将成为时间的囚犯
or we and our reluctant passengers will remain its prisoners.
我们只有一个理论和一些事实
All we have is a theory and a few facts.
我和史考特都认为唯一的解决方案
Mr. Scott and I both agree that the only possible solution
是用弹弓效应，怎么来就怎么去
is a slingshot effect like the one that put us here.
运算显示若我们驶向太阳
My computations indicate that if we fly toward the sun,
被其磁场牵制后，开足动力反向飞行
seek out its magnetic attraction, then pull away at full power,
挣脱瞬间产生的力量，能把我们带到另一个时空
the whiplash will propel us into another time warp.
弹弓效应对你们管用
Slingshot effects are fine for you people.
那我和中士该怎么回去？
How do you propose to return the sergeant and me?
逻辑上，随着我们朝太阳越飞越快
Logically, as we move faster and faster toward the sun,
时间便开始倒流
we'll begin to move backward in time.
我们实际是回到昨天之前
We'll actually go back beyond yesterday.
回到我们在天空出现前的时刻
Beyond the point when we first appeared in the sky.
这样才能回到未来
Then breaking free will shoot us forward in time,
在那之前，我们会把你们送回去
and we'll transport you back at a point before any of this happened.
你们什么都不会记得，因为一切从未发生
You won't have anything to remember because it never will have happened.
若不能挣脱太阳呢？
What if you can't pull free of the sun?
我们会小心的，上校
Oh, we'll do that all right, captain.
不会靠得太近，否则轮机无法挣脱
We'll not be getting so close that my engines couldn't pull us out.
我担心的是挣脱之后
What I am worried about, sir, is that we may not have much control
- 飞船可能会失控 - 控制船舵？
- when we're thrown forward again. - Helm control?
控制制动，长官
Braking control, sir.
制动不及时的话，可能会超过我们的时代
If I can't stop us soon enough, we may overshoot our time.
制动太突然，惯性的张力又会把船撕碎
And if I stop the engines suddenly, the strain may tear us apart.
不管怎么做，都是凶多吉少
Any way we do it, it means a mighty rough ride.
好吧，先生们，只有碰碰运气了
Well, gentlemen, we all have to take a chance...
尤其现在只有唯一的机会
...especially if one is all you have.
各就各位
Assume your stations.
- 曲速三前进，苏鲁 - 曲速三，长官
- Ahead warp factor 3, Mr. Sulu. - Warp factor 3, sir.
我从未想过能进入太空
I never thought I'd make it into space.
我曾是航天计划候选人
I was in line to be chosen for the space programme...
- 但我没合格 - 好好看看，上校
- ...but I didn't qualify. - Take a good look around, captain.
你比他们早进了太空
You made it here ahead of all of them.
长官，正在加速中，航速超过曲速八
Sir, our speed is increasing. We're travelling at more than warp 8.
- 史波克先生？ - 刚飞过水星后
- Mr. Spock? - Since we've passed Mercury,
太阳引力开始剧增
the sun's pull on us has increased greatly.
从这之后，速度会更快
From here, we'll move even faster.
上校，注意计时器，时间开始倒流
And, captain, notice the chronometers. They've started backward.
一分一分倒流，速度开始加快
Minute by minute, the speed of time passage will now increase.
拿好装备去传送室报道
Get your gear and report to the Transporter Room.
克里斯托弗上校，您只有十五年时间准备
And Captain Christopher, you only have about 15 years,
最好快点
so you better hurry.
接近脱离点，开始计时
Approaching breakaway point. On the countdown.
10、9
Ten, nine,
8、7、6
eight, seven, six,
5、4、3、2
five, four, three, two,
- 1 - 就是现在，苏鲁
- one. - Now, Mr. Sulu.
加大动力，苏鲁
More power, Mr. Sulu.
已是最大了，长官，她在努力！
It's maximum now, sir. She's fighting it.
确认引力降至0.8
We confirm, gravity is down to 0.8.
- 成功逃离，开始返回 - 加速中，舰长
- We've broken free and heading back. - Gaining speed now, captain.
正以曲速四行进
We're now at warp 4.
曲速七
Warp 7.
曲速八
Eight.
开始读秒，长官
Off the dial, sir.
计时器恢复正常，舰长
Chronometers moving forward again, Captain.
你有遣返克里斯托弗上校
You have the chronometer reading
和警卫的坐标和时间吗？
and the coordinates to return Captain Christopher and the guard?
算过了
Computed.
舰桥呼叫传送室，克里斯托弗上校？
Bridge to Transporter Room. Captain Christopher?
我是克里斯托弗
This is Christopher.
我们马上就接近地球了，准备好了吗？
We're coming up on Earth fast, captain. Are you ready?
一切就绪
Everything A-okay.
舰长，谢谢让我开了眼界
Captain, thanks for the look ahead.
不客气，上校，通话完毕
Our pleasure, captain. Bridge out.
还有二十分钟，越来越近了
Twenty minutes, sir. It'll be close.
舰桥呼叫传送室
Bridge to Transporter Room.
准备传送
Prepare to energise.
十分钟
Ten minutes.
9、8、7
Nine, eight, seven,
6、5
six, five,
- 4、3、2、1 - 开始
- four, three, two, one. - Energise.
距离很近，目标就在视线范围内
You should be close enough for visual contact.
蓝鸟四号，听得见吗？
Blue Jay Four, can you see it?
是什么？
What is it?
蓝鸟四号，听到请讲，目标画面消失
Blue Jay Four, come in. We've lost the image.
蓝鸟四号呼叫黑鹰
Blackjack, this is Blue Jay Four.
我发誓刚有架像飞船的东西
I could've sworn there was some kind of ship,
但不可能飞这么快
but nothing could've moved that fast.
别又是什么幻象
We don't track mirages.
就当是架UFO
Mark it down as another UFO
蓝鸟四号返航
Blue Jay Four returning to base.
通话完毕
Out.
接近第二个传送点，舰长
Approaching second beaming, captain.
舰桥呼叫传送室，准备传送
Bridge to Transporter Room, prepare to energise.
- 现在 - 传送
- Now. - Energise.
飞过冥王星了，长官
Passed Pluto, sir.
时间读数，史波克？
What's our reading, Mr. Spock?
正前往我们的年代，舰长
Approaching our century, captain.
现在准备制动
Braking should begin...now.
舰桥呼叫轮机室
Bridge to Engineering,
全力制动
begin full braking power.
挣脱太阳使轮机变弱，长官
Pulling away from the sun weakened them, sir.
- 制动可能会爆炸 - 别无选择，史考特
- They may blow apart if I reverse. - No choice, Mr. Scott.
是，长官
Aye, sir.
- 还有五十年 - 轮机动力减弱
- Fifty years to go. - Engines cutting back, sir.
- 没有降速 - 四十年
- No decrease in speed. - Forty.
- 三十年 - 别管了，史波克
- Thirty. - Never mind, Mr. Spock.
轮机
The engines.
轮机室呼叫舰桥
Engineer to bridge.
轮机正全速回转
Engines are on full reverse.
快撑不住了
They're buckling.
舰桥！
Bridge!
史考特没事
Mr. Scott is still with us.
- 舰长 - 星际舰队控制中心呼叫进取号
- Captain. - Starfleet Control calling Enterprise.
- 呼叫进取号 - 打开频道，乌乎拉
- Come in, Enterprise. - Open a channel, Uhura.
已开启，长官
Frequency open, sir.
星际舰队控制中心，这里是进取号
Starfleet Control, this is the Enterprise,
寇克舰长请求通话
Captain Kirk speaking.
飞船的到达已记录，亲爱的
Record ship arrival, dear.
进取号，这里是星际舰队控制中心
Enterprise, this is starfleet Control.
- 欢迎回来 - 星际舰队控制中心，再次重复
- Come in, please. - Starfleet Control, repeating message.
进取号回家了
The Enterprise is home.
通话完毕
Kirk out.
本集结束